Guide to the South Africa Now Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Interviews, 1978-1991, undated; Series V
  - Tapes F235-F236: Dinkins and United Democratic Front (UDF) Leaders press conference, tapes 1-2, 1989 January 30; 2 (Box 728–729)
  - Tape F237: Pik-Botha in halls of United Nations (UN), Undated; 1 (Box 730)
  - Tape F238: Jim and Tammy Baker from Nightline, 1987 May 27; 1 (Box 731)
  - Tape F239: Stevie Wonder at United Nations (UN), Undated; 1 (Box 732)
  - Tape F240: David Turnley interview, segments 3-6, 1988 September 1; 1 (Box 733)
  - African-American Institute (AAI) conference, Lusaka, Zambia, 1989 January 9-13
    - Tape F241: Interviewees, tape 1 of 25, 1 (Box 734)
    - Tape F242: Press conference with Jackson and Tambo, host: Thabo Mbeki, tape 2 of 25, 1 (Box 735)
    - Tapes F243-F244: Press conference, tapes 3 and 4 of 25, 2 (Box 736–737)
    - Tapes F245-F246: Kaunda speech, tapes 5 and 6 of 25, 2 (Box 738–739)
    - Tapes F247-F248: Kaunda, tapes 7 and 8 of 25, 2 (Box 740–741)
      Tape F248 (box 741) lacks audio for several minutes.
    - Tapes F249-F250: Ameen Akalwaya, tapes 9 and 10 of 25, 2 (Box 742–743)
    - Tape F251: Mulungushi Hall exterior, tape 12 of 25, 1 (Box 744)
    - Tape F253-F255: Jesse Jackson keynote speech, tapes 14-16 of 25, 3 (Box 745–747)
    - Tape F256: Jackson interview (no sound), tape 17 of 25, 1 (Box 748)
      The tape lacks audio at start of content.
    - Tape F257: Mark Charo and Mohammed [Valli Moosa] (no sound), tape 18 of 25, 1 (Box 749)
    - Tape F258: Mohammed [Valli Moosa] and Murphy Marobe (no sound), tape 19 of 25, 1 (Box 750)
      The audio in the tape is defective.
    - Tape F259: Roger Wilkins, Tom Winshop, Les Payne, Sisulu, Slabbert, tape 20 of 25, 1 (Box 751)
    - Tape F260: Slabbert, Nugent, Hearn, tape 21 of 25, 1 (Box 752)
    - Tapes F261-F262: more interviews and closing remarks, tapes 22 and 23 of 25, 2 (Box 753–754)
    - Tape F263: B-roll, tape 24 of 25, 1 (Box 755)
    - Tape F264: Thabo Mbeki, tape 25 of 25, 1 (Box 756)
  - Tapes F265-F266: Frank Ferrari, 1989 February 3; 2 (Box 757–758)
  - Tapes F266-F268: Chikane press conference, 1989 February 3; 3 (Box 758–760)
  - Tape F269: Oumarou Youssoufou, 1989 February 3; 1 (Box 761)
    See also: Tapes F490-F491, boxes 962-963 and Tape F497, box 969.
  - Tape F280: Tony Weaver stand up, 1989 February 2; 1 (Box 762)
  - Tape F281: Ameen Akhalwaya, 1989 January 31; 1 (Box 763)
  - Steve Askin
    - Tape F282: Sanctions busting (first 5 minutes), 1989 February 3; 1 (Box 764)
    - Tape F283: Graphics, 1989 February 3; 1 (Box 765)
  - Tape F284: Mbongeni Mgema, 1989 February 8; 1 (Box 766)
  - Tape F285: Eddie, detainees parents? press conference, 1989 February 8; 1 (Box 767)
  - Tape F285a: Parents? press conference, re-transfer, 1989 February 13; 1 (Box 768)
  - Tape F286: Donna Katzin, 1989 February 10; 1 (Box 769)
  - Tapes F287-F288: Gay McDougal, tapes 1-2, 1989 February 10; 2 (Box 770–771)
    See also tapes F523-F525, boxes 994-996, F741-F742, boxes 1196-1197, and F977, box 1398.
  - Tapes F289-F290: Man on street, re: Jackson and African-Americans vs. Black Americans, tapes 1-2, 1989 February 11; 2 (Box 772–773)
  - Tapes F291-F293: Francis Wilson, tapes 1-3, Undated; 3 (Box 774–776)
  - Tapes F294-F296: Mamphela Ramphele, tapes 1-3, Undated; 3 (Box 777–779)
  - Tapes F297-310, F312-F314: NRB (National Religious Broadcasters?), tapes 1-14 and 16-18, 1989 February 2; 17 (Box 780–796)
  - Tape F315: Larry Jones [first nine minutes], Undated; 1 (Box 797)
  - Tape F316: Eddie and Ameen -- Olivier Forsyth; National Party (NP) new leader and P. W. Botha; Asvat's memorial service, 1989 February 10; 1 (Box 798)
  - Tapes F317-F318: William M. Ramoshaba -- South African businessmen, tapes 1-2, 1989 February 13; 2 (Box 799–800)
  - Tape F319: Carolyn Craven, 1989 February 16; 1 (Box 801)
    There is no audio at the beginning of the tape.
  - Tape F320: Tsietsi Maleho interview by C. Craven on hunger strike to free Mandela and Winnie Mandela, 1989 February 16; 1 (Box 802)
  - Tape F321: Roy Innes, 1989 February 17; 1 (Box 803)
  - Tape F324: E. Nadler and Dick Leonard, 1989 February 16; 1 (Box 804)
  - Tape F330: Kandetu, 1989 February 22; 1 (Box 805)
  - Tapes F331-F332: Tom Lodge, tapes 1-2, 1989 February 29; 2 (Box 806–807)
  - Tape F333: Adotei Akwe, 1989 February 27; 1 (Box 808)
  - Tapes F334-F335: Annika Claasens, tapes 1-2, 1989 March 2; 2 (Box 809–810)
  - Tapes F336-F337: Miriam Lacob -- Africa Watch, tapes 1-2, 1989 March 2; 2 (Box 811–812)
  - Tape F338: Paul Simon; Don Stillman, 1989 March 4; 1 (Box 813)
  - Tapes F339-F341: Kosisaka, tapes 1-3, 1989 March 4; 3 (Box 814–816)
  - Tapes F342-F343: Yair Tzaban, tapes 1-2, 1989 March 9; 2 (Box 817–818)
  - Tape F344: Gary Jordan, 1989 March 8; 1 (Box 819)
  - Tape F344a: Gary Jordan, Undated; 1 (Box 820)
  - Tapes F345-F347: Elite Modeling Agency, including John Casablancas, tapes 1-3, 1989 March 10; 3 (Box 821–823)
  - Tapes F348-F350: Jonathan Shapiro, tapes 1-3, 1989 March 17; 3 (Box 824–826)
  - Tape F351: Uriel Savir, 1989 March 13; 1 (Box 827)
  - Tape F352: Eddie; detainees released, 1989 March 6; 1 (Box 828)
  - Tape F353: Jane Hunter, 1989 March 17; 1 (Box 829)
  - Tape F354: Bill Howard at Interfaith Center on Corporate Responsibility (ICCR), 1989 March 20; 1 (Box 830)
  - Tapes F355-F357: Johnson Mlambo, tapes 1-3, 1989 March 22; 3 (Box 831–833)
  - Tapes F358-F359: Blade Nzimande, 1989 March 23; 2 (Box 834–835)
  - Tapes F360-F361: Detainees press conference, parts 1-2, 1989 March 23; 2 (Box 836–837)
  - Tape F362: Bill Minter on Mozambique and Angola, 1989 March 27; 1 (Box 838)
  - Phyllis Johnson and David Martin, 1989 March 27
    - Tapes F363-F364: Camera 1 (2-shot), 2 (Box 839–840)
    - Tapes F365-F366: Camera 2 (single shot), 2 (Box 841–842)
  - Tapes F367-F368: Richard Knight, 1989 March 31; 2 (Box 843–844)
  - Tape F368: Govin Reddy, 1989 March 31; 1 (Box 844)
  - Tape F369: Govin Reddy with Mwezi; stills of South Africa, 1989 March 31; 1 (Box 845)
  - Washington, D.C.
    - Tape F370: State Department exterior, tape 1, 1989 March 22; 1 (Box 846)
    - Tapes F370-F371: Admiral La Roque, tapes 1-2, 1 (Box 846–847)
    - Tapes F371-F372: Tom Allen, tapes 2-3, 1 (Box 847–848)
    - Tape F373: South African Embassy, tape 4, 1 (Box 849)
    - Tape F374: Attache's home; Harold Glaser, lawyer, tape 5, 1 (Box 850)
    - Tapes F375: Mail House in Baltimore; Havre de Grace, tape 6, 1 (Box 851)
    - Tape F376: C. Wiggins (neighbor); phone booth dramatization, tape 7, 1 (Box 852)
  - Tapes F377-F378: Alain Roberts (on Namibia), tapes 1-2, 1989 April 6; 2 (Box 853–854)
  - New York Labor Community Against Apartheid, tapes 1-3, 1989 April 7
    - Tape F379: Interviews with Mrs. Mayekiso and W. Henning, tape 1, 1 (Box 855)
    - Tape F380: Choirs and speeches, tape 2, 1 (Box 856)
    - Tape F381: Interviews with Mrs. Mayekiso, tape 3, 1 (Box 857)
  - Tape F382: Theo-Ben Gurirab at United Nations (UN), 1989 April 3; 1 (Box 858)
  - Tape F383: Reverend Zuze, 1989 April 5; 1 (Box 859)
  - Tapes F384-F387: Theo-Ben Gurirab with J. Diescho, tapes 1A, 1B, 2A, and 2B, 1989 April 10; 4 (Box 860–863)
  - Tape F388: Toni Strasburg, 1989 April 13; 1 (Box 864)
  - Tape F389: U.S. Attorney Mulroney, 1989 April 13; 1 (Box 865)
  - Tape F390: Naomi Tutu, 1989 April 13; 1 (Box 866)
  - Tape F391: David Seftel, 1989 April 13; 1 (Box 867)
  - Tapes F392-F397: Donald Woods briefing at Congress, tapes 1-6, 1989 April 3; 6 (Box 868–873)
  - Tape F398: Columbia University: Bob Rosenthal, editor, Philadelphia Enquirer; former Ambassador to South Africa, 1989 April 14; 1 (Box 874)
  - Tapes F400-F401: Elizabeth Landis, tapes 1-2, 1989 April 18; 2 (Box 875–876)
  - Tape F402: Angus Stewart; National Union of South African Students (NUSAS), 1989 April 19; 1 (Box 877)
  - Tapes F403-F405: Sibusiso Sithole, tapes 1-3, 1989 April 19; 3 (Box 878–880)
  - Tape F406: Jeff Cohen: media specialist, Fairness and Accuracy in Reporting (FAIR), 1989 April 21; 1 (Box 881)
  - Tapes F407-F408: Jeremy Sterns, independent South African filmmaker, tapes 1-2, 1989 April 21; 2 (Box 882–883)
  - Tape F409: Donald Wood, Danny Schechter; Quoboza; Union, 1978; 1 (Box 884)
  - Tapes F410-F412: Sonny Venkatrathnam: former detainee, tapes 1-3, 1989 April 27; 3 (Box 885–887)
  - Tapes F413-F414: Donna Katzin, tapes 1-2, 1989 April 27; 2 (Box 888–889)
  - Tape F415: Congressman Rangle, 1989 April 28; 1 (Box 890)
  - Tapes F416-F417: Ballistics expert -- Joseph W. Quick (NYPD), tapes 1-2, 1989 April 24; 2 (Box 891–892)
    Tape F416 (box 891) contains a six-minute break in the audio.
  - Tape F418: David Webster, 1989 May 1; 1 (Box 893)
  - Tapes F420-F422: Albie Sachs, tapes 1-3, 1989 May 4; 3 (Box 894–896)
  - Tape F423: Bill Nottingham on murder of Reverend Wayne Steinert; Khotso House bombing; clips and interviews with Director Bernard Spong, Interchurch Media, and Production Technician Peter Shomong, Interchurch Media Program, 1989 May 6; 1 (Box 897)
  - Tapes F424-F427: Lewis Nkosi, 1989 May 8; 4 (Box 898–901)
  - Tape F428: George Clinton, Undated; 1 (Box 902)
  - Tapes F430-F431: Zuze, Zambian Embassy, tapes 1-2, [No year] May 5; 2 (Box 903–904)
  - Tape F432: Jimmy Carter at CNN World Report Conference, Undated; 1 (Box 905)
  - Red Scorpions
    - Tape F433: Stand ups, 1989 April 20; 1 (Box 906)
    - Tape F434: MOS, 1989 April 20; 1 (Box 907)
  - Tapes F435-F436: Paula Bauer: Education Against Apartheid, 1989 May 9; 2 (Box 908–909)
  - Tape F437: Rick Ducta (on Laura Branigan playing Sun City), 1989 May 12; 1 (Box 910)
  - Tape F438: CNN Contributors Conference: Jesse Jackson speech, 1989 May 5; 1 (Box 911)
  - Tape F439: Jackson Swartz: three interviews, Undated; 1 (Box 912)
  - Tapes F440-F442: Vusi Khanyile -- National Education Crisis Committee (NECC), tapes 1-3, 1989 May 16; 3 (Box 913–915)
  - Tapes F443-F444: Rudzani Nemasetonia (artist), tapes 1-2, 1989 May 18; 2 (Box 916–917)
  - Tape F445: High school debate on South Africa (New York City), Undated; 1 (Box 918)
    The tapes contains two break in the audio at approximately 13 minutes and 18 minutes.
  - Tape F446: Dr. Jane Smith -- Harlem Hospital, 1989 March; 1 (Box 919)
  - Tapes F447-F449: Trans-Africa -- Tutu Press Conference, tapes 1-3, 1989 May 17; 3 (Box 920–922)
  - Tapes F450-F450a: Gary Hilberry, Special Agent of Customs, 1989 May 21; 2 (Box 923–924)
    Tape F450 (box 923) contains frequent breaks in the audio..
  - Tape F451: Chuck D and Sting for South Africa Now, Undated; 1 (Box 925)
  - Tapes F452-F454: Lucky Dube, tapes 1a, 1b, and 2, 1989 May 22; 3 (Box 926–928)
  - Tapes F455-F458: Senti Thobejane (re: Soweta education), tapes 1-4, 1989 May 25; 4 (Box 929–932)
  - Tape F459: Beyers Naude, 1989 May 30; 1 (Box 933)
  - Tapes F460-F463: Reverend Allan Boesak, Riverside Church vigil and celebration of protest with cast of Sarafina and Peter, Paul, and Mary, tapes 1-4, 1989 June 5; 4 (Box 934–937)
  - Tapes F464-F467: Bill Ainsley, Johannesburg Arts Foundation, tapes 1-4, 1989 June 7; 4 (Box 938–941)
  - Tapes F468-F471: Frank Chikane Press Corporation, tapes 1-4, 1989 June 7; 4 (Box 942–945)
  - Tapes F472-F473: Curtis Nkondo, tapes 1-2, 1989 June 9; 2 (Box 946–947)
  - Tapes F474-F476: Lorraine Klaasen, tapes 1-3, 1989 June 17; 3 (Box 948, Box 948A, Box 949)
  - Tapes F478-F481: Archie Singham and Diescho, tapes 1-4, 1989 June 12; 4 (Box 950–953)
  - Tape F482: Philadelphia Inquirer reporter; Mazizi Kunene, University of California, Los Angeles (U.C.L.A), 1989 June; 1 (Box 954)
  - Tapes F483-F484: John Hammock, tapes 1-2, 1989 June 19; 2 (Box 955–956)
  - Tapes F485-F487: Mothopeng -- press packet, tapes 1-3, 1989 June 19; 3 (Box 957–959)
  - Tapes F488-F489: Mahlatini, tapes 1-2, 1989 June 21; 2 (Box 960–961)
  - Tapes F490-F491: Oumarou Youssoufou, tapes 1-2, 1989 June 22; 2 (Box 962–963)
    See also: Tape F269, box 761 and Tape F497, box 969.
  - Tapes F492-F493: Herman Cohen, U.S. State Department, tapes 1-2, 1989 June 23; 2 (Box 964–965)
  - Tapes F494-F496: Simon Ntombela -- South African Youth Congress (SAYCO) publicity, tapes 1-3, 1989 June 22; 3 (Box 966–968)
  - Tape F497: Youssoufou at United Nations (UN), 1989 June 23; 1 (Box 969)
    See also: Tape 269, box 761 and Tapes F490-491, boxes 962-963.
  - Tapes F498-F499: Helmut Angula -- South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO) farewell in New York City, tapes 1-2, 1989 June 23; 2 (Box 970–971)
  - Tapes F500-F501: Lorraine Klaasen, South African musician, tapes 1-2, 1989 June 29; 2 (Box 972–973)
  - Tape F502: Jonas Gwangwa (musician), 1989 June 30; 1 (Box 974)
    The tape contains a five-minute break in the audio beginning at 18:21 minutes.
  - Tape F503: Richard Dicker, 1989 June 26; 1 (Box 975)
  - Tapes F505-F508: Sisulu delegation, tapes 2-5, 1989 July 5; 4 (Box 976–979)
  - Tapes F509-F510: Helmut Angula, tapes 1-2, 1989 July 6; 2 (Box 980–981)
  - Tapes F511-F512: Tom Lodge, United Nations (UN), tapes 1-2, 1989 July 12; 2 (Box 982–983)
  - Tapes F513-F514: "Pan" -- African National Congress (ANC) Report, tapes 1-2, 1989 July 12; 2 (Box 984–985)
  - Lethal Weapon II
    See also: Tapes F521-F522, boxes 992-993.
    - Tape F515: Interviews with audience, 1989 July 12; 1 (Box 986)
    - Tape F516: Interviews with critic Stuart Klawans, 1989 July 12; 1 (Box 987)
  - Transnational Corporations
    - Tape F517: Computer Graphics, tape 1 of 4, 1989 July 13; 1 (Box 988)
    - Tape F518: Interview with Peter Hansen, tape 2 of 4, 1989 July 13; 1; videotape (v-30h) (Box 989)
    - Tapes F519-F520: Interview with David Hawk, tapes 3 and 4, 1989 July 13; 2 (Box 990–991)
  - Tapes F521-F522: Lethal Weapon II interview with Angolan Ambassador Manuel Pacavira, 1989 July 14; 2 (Box 992–993)
    See also: Tapes F515-F516, boxes 986-987.
  - Tapes F523-F525: Gay McDougal, 1989 July 21; 3 (Box 994–996)
    See also tapes F287-F288, boxes770-771, F741-F742, boxes 1196-1197, and F977, box 1398.
  - Tapes F526-F528: Geri Augusto; Enrique Chatas, 1989 July 21; 3 (Box 997–999)
  - Tapes F529-F530: Terry Crawford Brown (banker and adviser to Tutu and Boesak), tapes 1-2, 1989 July 26; 2 (Box 1000–1001)
  - Tape F540: Living Color -- New Music Seminar with Sting, 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 1002)
  - Tape F541: Norman Mingyim (South African lawyer -- "New Nation"), 1989 July 27; 1 (Box 1003)
  - Tapes F542-F543: Holland Commission on Apartheid re: oil embargo, 1989 July 28; 2 (Box 1004–1005)
  - Tapes F544-F546: Johnny Clegg -- New Music Seminar, tapes 1-3, 1989 July 18; 3 (Box 1006–1008)
  - Tape F547: Robert Whitehall [re: South African oil embargo], 1989 July 17; 1 (Box 1009)
  - Tape F548: Stansfield Turner, ex-CIA director [re: Vela blast], 1989 July 17; 1 (Box 1010)
  - Tape F549: Girard Smith, 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 1011)
  - Tape F550: Leonard Spector -- Carnegie Endowment, 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 1012)
  - Tape F551: Leonard Spector, Richard Betts -- Brookings Institution, 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 1013)
  - Tape F552: Richard Betts, Ron Walters -- Howard University, 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 1014)
  - Tape F553: Ron Walters [re: South Africa's nuclear program], 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 1015)
  - Tape F554: Ron Walters (cover shots), 1989 July 18; 1 (Box 1016)
  - Tapes F555-F556: Interview with Democratic Turnahalle Alliance (DTA) representative, tapes 1-2, 1989 August 7; 2 (Box 1017–1018)
  - Tape F557: David Albright (nuclear physicist), Undated; 1 (Box 1019)
  - Tapes F558-F560: Ralston Deffenbaugh, Director, Lutheran Office for World Community, tapes 1-3, 1989 August 11; 3 (Box 1020–1022)
  - Tape F561: Rapu Molekane -- student leader for South African Youth Congress (SAYCO), 1989 August 15; 1 (Box 1023)
  - Tape F562: Tom Lodge, 1989 August 15; 1 (Box 1024)
  - Tapes F563-F566: Afrocentricity Sikhulu, tapes 1-4, 1989 August 15; 4 (Box 1025–1028)
    Tapes 3 and 4 include MOS.
  - Tapes F567-F568: Michael Clough, 1989 August 17; 2 (Box 1029–1030)
  - Tapes F569-F570: Dan Mafole, African National Congress (ANC), tapes 1-2, [No year] August 22-23; 2 (Box 1031–1032)
  - Tapes F571-F572: Barney Simon, Director, Market Theatre, tapes 1-2, 1989 August 25; 2 (Box 1033–1034)
  - Tape F573: Arthur Ashe, 1989 August 25; 1 (Box 1035)
  - Tape F574: Mpho Tutu, [No year] August 31; 1 (Box 1036)
  - Tapes F576-F577: Street interviews on election day, tapes 1-2, 1989 September 2; 2 (Box 1037–1038)
  - Tape F578: Moses Mayekiso (London), 1989 September 1; 1 (Box 1039)
  - Tape F579: David Lourie, 1989 September 1; 1 (Box 1040)
  - Tape F583: Alan Roberts [re: Anton Lubowski], 1989 September 13; 1 (Box 1041)
  - Tapes F584-F585: Silvio Betti, tapes 1-2, 1989 September 113; 2 (Box 1042–1043)
  - Tape F586: Biko Lives Festival (Sting, Joe Papp), 1989 September 13; 1 (Box 1044)
  - Tapes F587-F588: Brian Sellars Petersen (Center for South African Ministry of Episcopal Church), tapes 1-2, 1989 September 13; 2 (Box 1045–1046)
  - Tape F589: Botswana President Masire, Hunger Prize, 1989 September 14; 1 (Box 1047)
  - Transnational Conference
    - Tape F590: South Africa hearings, closing press conference, tape 1 of 5, 1989 September 13; 1 (Box 1048)
    - Tape F591: Closing press conference, tape 2 of 5, 1989 September 13; 1 (Box 1049)
    - Tape F592: Ambassador Joseph Garba, United Nations (UN) Special Commission Against Apartheid, tape 3 of 5, 1989 September 13; 1 (Box 1050)
    - Tape F593: Merle Lipton; Jennifer Kibbe; Eugene Nyati, tape 4 of 5, 1989 September 13; 1 (Box 1051)
    - Tape F594: Barney Pityana; World Council of Churches, tape 5 of 5, 1989 September 13; 1 (Box 1052)
  - Tapes F595-F597: Finzer, unregistered lobbyist for South African Government, tapes 1-3, 1989 September 15; 3 (Box 1053–1055)
  - Dry White Season
    - Tape F598: Euzhan Palcy, director, 1989 September 15; 1 (Box 1056)
    - Tapes F599-F600: Zakes Mokae and Paula Weinstein, 1989 September 15; 2 (Box 1057–1058)
  - Tape F601: Winston Nagan, president, Amnesty International, 1989 September 15; 1 (Box 1059)
  - Tape F602: Bernard Rivers -- oil, 1989 August [29]; 1 (Box 1060)
  - Tape F603: Arthur Klinghoffer -- oil, 1989 August 21; 1 (Box 1061)
  - Tapes F604-F605: Ambassador Joseph Garba, tapes 1-2, 1989 August 18; 2 (Box 1062–1063)
  - Tape F605: Eric Nadler oil stand up, 1989 August 18; 1 (Box 1063)
  - Tapes F606-F607: Bishop Browning, Bishop of United States Episcopalian Church, tapes 1-2, 1989 September 18; 2 (Box 1064–1065)
  - Tape F608: Ziggy Marley, 1989 September 18; 1 (Box 1066)
  - Tape F609: John Hammond and Oxfam representatives, 1989 September 18; 1 (Box 1067)
  - Tape F610: Anton Lubowski, 1989 August 11; 1 (Box 1068)
  - Tapes F611-F612: Elsie Washington and Dwight Carter, 1989 September 21; 2 (Box 1069–1070)
  - Tapes F613-F614: Nomgcobo Sangweni, 1989 September 21; 2 (Box 1071–1072)
  - Tapes F615-F616: Rudzani Nemasetoni -- artist, 1989 September 22; 2 (Box 1073–1074)
  - Tapes F617-F618: Wendy Newstadt -- teacher, dancer, 1989 September 22; 2 (Box 1075–1076)
  - Tapes F619-F621: "Women's Struggle" -- African National Congress (ANC) member Nomazizi Sokudela, 1989 September 26; 3 (Box 1077–1079)
    The left audio channel on Tape F620 (box 1078) contains static noise, the right channel is not affected.
  - Tapes F622-F623: Martin Thomas (resisted conscription into the South African Army), 1989 September 26; 2 (Box 1080–1081)
  - Tape F624: Priscilla Jana (South African lawyer), 1989 September 27; 1 (Box 1082)
  - Tape F625: Lindiwe Mabuza (poet, African National Congress [ANC] representative), 1989 September 27; 1 (Box 1083)
  - Tape F626: George Bizos (South African lawyer), 1989 September 27; 1 (Box 1084)
  - Columbia University
    - Tape F627: Thabo Mbeki and Herman Cohen, 1989 September 26; 1 (Box 1085)
    - Tape F628: Audrey Coleman, 1989 September 27; 1 (Box 1086)
  - Tape F629: Thabo Mbeki, 1989 September 28; 1 (Box 1087)
  - Tapes F630-F632: Columbia -- Human Rights Conference, tapes 1-3, 1989 September 29; 3 (Box 1088–1090)
    Box 1090 also includes Albie Sachs interview.
  - Tape F633: Interview with Foreign Minister of Angola, 1989 October 2; 1 (Box 1091)
  - Nathan Shamuyarira, Zimbabwe Minister of Foreign Affairs
    - Tapes F634-F636: Speech, 1989 October 3; 3 (Box 1092–1094)
    - Tapes F637-F638: Interview, Undated; 2 (Box 1095–1096)
  - Tape F639: South African policy, foreign affairs: Kennedy, Cohen, Herman, 1989 October 3; 1 (Box 1097)
  - Tapes F640-F642: Ina Perlman -- South Africa Hunger Project, 1989 October 6; 3 (Box 1098–1100)
  - Tapes F643-F659: Geneva Conference, tapes 1-17, 1989 September 4; 17 (Box 1101–1117)
  - Tapes F660-F661: David Lurie, Undated; 2 (Box 1118–1119)
  - Tapes F662-F665: Tony Bird, 1989 September 13; 4 (Box 1120–1123)
  - Tapes F666-F670: Raymond Suttner, Undated; 5 (Box 1124–1128)
  - Tape F671: Rapu Molekane, student leader of SAYCO (South African Youth Congress), 1989 October 11; 1 (Box 1129)
  - Tape F672: Ahmad Gora Ebrahim, 1989 October 11; 1 (Box 1130)
  - Tape F673:Tebogo Mafole; George Bizos, 1989 October 11; 1 (Box 1131)
  - Tapes F674-F675: Bryce (draft resister) Interview, Undated; 2 (Box 1132–1133)
  - Tapes F676-F677: Henry Ludski -- South African journalist, 1989 October 16; 2 (Box 1134–1135)
  - Tapes F678-F679: Helen Suzman, 1989 October 17; 2 (Box 1136–1137)
  - Tapes F680-F681: Press conference on Angolan Health Emergency -- Commission on Racial Justice, Undated; 2 (Box 1138–1139)
  - Tapes F682-F884: Jesse Jackson, Namibia (United Nations), 1989 October 19; 3 (Box 1140–1142)
  - Tapes F685-F686: David Jackson, Interview -- South Africa Now, 1989 October 23; 2 (Box 1143–1144)
  - Tape F687: Interview with Jabu Khanyile of the South African Musicians Union, 1989 October 23; 1 (Box 1145)
  - Tapes F688-F690: Helen Suzman: Kennedy Lecture, 1989 October 24; 3 (Box 1146–1148)
  - Ford Foundation
    - Tape F691: Anthony Lake, 1989 October 25; 1 (Box 1149)
    - Tapes F692-F693: Pauline Baker, 1989 October 25; 2 (Box 1150–1151)
  - Tapes F694-F696: Keyan Tomaselli, 1989 October 26; 3 (Box 1152–1154)
  - Tapes F697-F699: Athol Fugard, 1989 October 26; 3 (Box 1155–1157)
  - Tapes F700-F702: Interview with Michael Judd [Peter Magubane, noted photographer], 1989 October 25; 3 (Box 1158–1160)
  - Tapes F703-F704: Vusiswe Players in White Plains, 1989 October 28; 2 (Box 1161–1162)
  - Tape F705: Elizabeth Landis -- Columbia University, 1989 September 26; 1 (Box 1163)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) [re: political asylum]
    - Tape F706: Craig Demmer, 1989 November 2; 1 (Box 1164)
    - Tape F707: LucasGuttenberg, 1989 November 2; 1 (Box 1165)
    - Tape F708: Craig Demm and Lucas Guttenberg b-roll, 1989 November 2; 1 (Box 1166)
  - Tapes F709-F710: United Nations (UN) special committee hearings, 1989 November 3; 2 (Box 1167–1168)
  - Tapes F711-F712: Miriam Tlali, 1989 November 4; 2 (Box 1169–1170)
  - Tape F714: Interview with Mr. Giuliani, spokesperson for the Secretary General of the United Nations (UN), Undated; 1 (Box 1171)
  - Tapes F715-F716: Miriam Makeba, 1989 November 7; 2 (Box 1172–1173)
  - Tapes F717-F719: African American Institute (AAI) Awards -- Jimmy Carter and Albertina Sisulu, 1989 November 8; 3 (Box 1174–1176)
  - Tapes F720-F721: Albertina Sisulu at United Nations Plaza Hotel, 1989 November 9; 2 (Box 1177–1178)
  - Tapes F722-F723: American Committee On Africa (ACOA), 1989 November 9; 2 (Box 1179–1180)
  - Tapes F724-F725: Linda Ellerbee, Undated; 2 (Box 1181–1182)
  - Tapes F728-F729: Joel Koval, 1989 November 14; 2 (Box 1183–1184)
  - Tape F730: Athol Fugard; John Kani, Undated; 1 (Box 1185)
  - Tapes F731-F733: Island Trading Company, 1989 November 22; 3 (Box 1186–1188)
  - Tape F734: Interviews with defendant in Manufacturers Hanover Trust, 1989 December 7; 1 (Box 1189)
  - Tape F735: Association of American Publishers, 1989 November 22; 1 (Box 1190)